everyclick.com 2019-12-28

# Privacy policy | Everyclick

### 1.0 Introduction __

This document details what information we may hold about you, why we hold it, and how we may use it. If you represent a charity, you may also wish to refer to our [charity privacy policy](https://ea.everyclick.com/cookies).

This policy applies to Everyclick ([www.everyclick.com](https://www.everyclick.com/)).

Everyclick is operated by Give as you Live Limited ('GAYL'). Your Everyclick account can also be used to access other products operated by GAYL. If you use any of these other products, additional policies may apply - you should check the relevant website(s) for those additional policies.

If you make a direct donation to charity, you'll be taken to the Give as you Live Donate website where its privacy policy will apply.

If you make use a Give as you Live shopping link when using Everyclick, then the Give as you Live privacy policy will apply.

When you use click on a search result, you are taken to another website where different terms and conditions, privacy policies, and cookie policies will apply.

This policy was last updated on 1st July 2019.

### 2.0 What information we store about you __

When you sign up to Everyclick, the only personal information we require are your name and email address. You also choose a password and select a charity to support.

If you sign-up using Facebook, we will store a link to your Facebook account and require you to provide the requested permissions (access to your full name and email address). If you deny or retract these permissions then you will be unable to access your Everyclick account.

Within your account, you may optionally provide more personal information such as your date of birth and gender. You may amend or remove this information at any time via your account.

We store information regarding your activity on Everyclick, including searches, donations, Give as you Live activity (including searches and tracked purchases), and technical information such as your browser and IP address. We may use external tools, such as Google Analytics, to collect such information.

If you enter a competition we run, then we may store information entered on the competition entry form. This is usually just an email address and name.

### 3.0 Why we can use information about you __

Data protection laws, including General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the Data Protection Act (DPA) 2018, require us to have a valid legal reason for using your information. You may find out more about these legal reasons [on the ICO website](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-data-protection/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/lawful-basis-for-processing/).

As per our terms and conditions, any use by you of our website or product consitutes acceptance of our terms and conditions. As such, your information is used to provide the services described by our terms, including the provision of fundraising pages and the payment of donations. Emails relating to your account or donations may also be sent by us to the email address you provide. This is to fulfil the **contract** that the terms and conditions serve as.

If your **consent** is provided (either at the point of signup or by updating your account), we may use your information to contact you regarding our product (or other products provided by GAYL) - see section 4.0 How we may contact you for more information.

If your **consent** is provided (either at the point of signup or by updating your account), we share your information with your chosen charity - see section 4.0 How we may contact you for more information.

For information regarding your activity, as described in section 2, we are using our **legitimate interest** to help us understand use of our product and behaviour of users; and to aid decision making regarding further development of our product in order to provide a better service to you and all our users.

### 4.0 How we may contact you __

To help you make the most of your fundraising and to maximise what you can raise for charity, we would like to contact you to keep you updated with Everyclick and other products that GAYL run.

You can provide your consent for this at the point of signup or from within your account. You can unsubscribe at any time, either using the 'unsubscribe' link in our emails or via your account.

Your opt-out status does not affect the sending of transactional emails - for example emails confirming a donation or emails relating to accessing your account.

If you contact us, for instance via phone or email, you give us permission to contact you relating to your query. Doing so will not result in your details being added to any promotional email lists.

If you are not signed up to Everyclick, but have entered a competition then you will agreed to our competition terms and conditions. This includes giving us permission to send you promotional emails relating to Everyclick and other products and services we may offer (including Give as you Live) - unless you opt out at the point of entry or at a later date.

If you have provided us with your contact information in person, for example at an industry event, then we may be able to contact you including sending a follow-up email or promotional emails. This will depend on the circumstances in which you provided your information.

### 5.0 How we use your information __

The personal information we store may be used to tailor our service to you. This could involve us displaying different content on our website based on your data and preferences.

We may also use your information - including personal, technical and usage data - for internal purposes such as statistical analysis. This is so that we can understand how our products and services are being used and to aid the decisions we make.

### 6.0 How data may be shared __

You can decide if your personal information is shared with your supported charity. This can be done at the point of sign-up or later via your account. The charity may therefore contact you and you will be subject to their own privacy policy.

Donation data is made accessible to charities - this data includes your name, email address and full address. Donation data for other Give as you Live products is also available to charities - this data is aggregated where appropriate. If you requested for your details not to be shared, then donation data will be anonymised (i.e. any identifing information such as names, emails or addresses are removed).

Please note that if you change your charity, your information will still be accessible to your previously supported charities (if you chose to share it with them). If you choose to withdraw your consent, please be aware that the charity may have already downloaded your information to their own systems. If you are concerned about this, please either contact us or contact the charity directly.

We may publicly display basic personal information - for example showing a list of recent donations including your name and amount raised. You have the option within your account to change your publically-displayed name or to change it to 'Anonymous'. If you don't have an account and are making a direct donation, you may choose to not have your name publically displayed.

We may use a variety of tools and services - including, but not limited to, email marketing tools, Facebook advertising tools, and Google advertising/analytical tools - which may involve uploading and processing your data in order to provide a service to us. Such tools may also track and record activity on our websites - doing so may involve the placing of cookies.

Outside of these scenarios, we do not pass your personal data onto any third parties without your explicit content.

### 7.0 Cookies __

Cookies are small text files placed on your computer by websites. The information cannot be seen by any other websites (so the information is secure) and is used by us to provide features to aid the use of our services.

Cookies need to be enabled in order for you to access your account, , whilst some functionality relies upon cookies. Therefore, the intended use of Everyclick requires cookies to be enabled.

For more information about how we use cookies, please see our cookie policy.

### 8.0 Security __

We endeavour to follow best practices and fulfil all legal obligations with regards to the security of your data and personal information.

In order to access your account with us, you choose a password which is used in combination with your email address to sign in with. It is also your responsibility to keep your password safe. If you use Facebook to log in to your account, the same applies to your Facebook access details.

We cannot take responsibility if you voluntarily or involuntarily enable someone else to access your account and gain access to any personal information stored.

You may change your password at any time via your account.

### 9.0 Access to information __

Your personal data belongs to you. You therefore have the right to request a copy of the personal information we hold about you. You may request this by contacting us. We do have the right to charge a fee or refuse unreasonable requests.

You also have the right to request that we remove any personal information we hold about you (known as "right to be forgotten" under GDPR). If you wish for us to remove your personal data, please contact us. Please note that this will result in the closure of your account, whilst non-personal information may be retained in an anonymised form. We will retain a record of your email address in our blacklist or opt-out lists. Following your initial request, we will contact you to verify your identify and to establish your wishes regarding any data previously shared with charities or retailers. Please note that we will be unable to fulfil the request without this verification.

### 10.0 Who we are and how to contact us __

Everyclick is operated by Give as you Live Limited, a registered company in England & Wales (company number 5181419), with registered offices at Basepoint Business Centre, Crab Apple Way, Vale Business Park, Evesham, Worcestershire, WR11 1GP, United Kingdom.

We are registered under the Data Protection Act, registration no. Z8852513.

Should you wish to contact us, please submit an enquiry via our help site.
